Dimitris Kottas

My professional experience and education in various design fields have given me multifaceted design skills that help me understand the needs and goals of different clients and provide solutions that are both technically correct and culturally relevant.

I have a long working experience of managing complex projects (such as book publications) from their initial conception and sketching until their end, collaborating with other professionals or working solo as required.

Through my work experience as book designer and editor I have learned to combine design and content management and editing, a skill that has proven very useful on consulting clients on how to best structure their content and creating the best design for delivering this content to its audience.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

2014-2015 Founder, designer and editor, Eccentric Books.

I have founded a small publishing house specializing in science fiction, fantasy and related genres.

2008 - 2014 Freelance web developer and designer.

I have designed and developed various websites for artists, companies, art galleries, news, etc.

2001 - 2010 Editor and book designer for Links Books.

I have worked on the design and editing of various architecture and design books such as: Digital Architecture: Design and Techniques, New Graphic Design: Corporate and Institutional Graphics, and more.

1999 - 2000 Architect at Andreadis-Tsiomis Office

I have worked as an architect on the landscape design project at the ancient Agora of Athens.

de Cultura Contemporánea de Barcelona (CCCB), Barcelona

EDUCATION

2015 - Started my Phd at the School of Architecture of the NTUA.

2000 – 2001 *"Metrópolis"*, **Master program** in Architecture and Urban Culture, Universidad Politécnica de Cataluña (UPC) - Centre

1990 – 1999 NTUA, Faculty of Architecture, **Architecture Diploma**

CONTACT

Address: Lomvardou 23-25, 11473,

Athens, Greece

E-mail: info@cuboctaedro.eu Website: www.cuboctaedro.eu

Phone: 0030 6932 001313

PERSONAL DATA

First name: Dimitrios Last name: Kottas Date of birth: 23/02/1973 Nationality: Greek

LANGUAGES

Greek: native English: fluent Spanish: fluent German: good Catalan: fair

PROGRAMMING

Excellent knowledge of:
HTML
CSS (LESS, Stylus)
Javascript (jQuery)
PHP
and various CMS programs like
Wordpress, Drupal and Kirby.

PROGRAMS

Excellent knowledge of: Adobe InDesign Adobe Illustrator Adobe Photoshop Microsoft Office